EDUARDO MANJARRES BARROS

(+57)314-627-2313

manjarreseduardo@outlook.com https://www.mycurriculumvitae.cloud/ Cra 42A #28-87, Soledad, Colombia

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Systems engineer with an emphasis on computer security with more than 5 years of experience in the area of information and communication technologies as well as extensive experience in the field of formal and distance education. My professional training led me to gain experience from different points of view at an operational and administrative level since I have several careers in the same area of technologies (Technologist in Analysis and Design of Information Systems, Specialist in database management and security , Technician in Computer Analysis and Programming). Thanks to this training and experience I have built a series of skills in graphic design (different tools such as the adobe suite) focused on vector design, website design, database management, computer security among other skills necessary for the revolution. of technologies or 4.0

WORK EXPERIENCE

USER SUPPORT TECHNICIAN

Aug 2022 - Present

ASGAN ATLANTICO • BARRANQUILLA, Colombia

- Communicate electronically and in person with computer users experiencing difficulties to determine and document problems experienced
- Consult user guides, technical manuals and other documents to research and implement solutions
- · Reproduce, diagnose and resolve technical problems encountered by users
- · Provide advice and training to users in response to identified difficulties
- Provide business systems, network and Internet support to users in response to identified difficulties
- Collect, organize and maintain a problems and solutions log for use by other technical support analysts
- Participate in the redesign of applications and other software
- · May supervise other technical support workers in this group.
- Design, develop, test, implement and oversee IT systems
- Collect and analyze data to identify areas for improvement within an organization's IT infrastructure
- Review existing IT systems and internal processes
- Develop, implement and apply policies and procedures throughout the software development life cycle to maximize the efficiency, effectiveness and overall quality of software products and information systems, and to ensure that all systems and processes meet organization standards and user requirements
- Develop quality assurance procedures and tests for the development and improvement of new and existing systems
- Identify, analyze and document discrepancies and ensure that appropriate adjustments are made

Perform preventive maintenance tasks on computer systems.

Teacher, college level (4021)

Aug 2020 - Apr 2021

CENTRO NACIONAL DE APRENDIZAJE SENA • Barranquilla, Colombia

- Teach students using a systematic plan of lectures, demonstrations, discussion groups, laboratory work, shop sessions, seminars, case studies, field assignments and independent or group projects
- Develop curriculum and prepare teaching materials and outlines for courses
- Prepare, administer and mark tests and papers to evaluate students' progress
- · Advise students on program curricula and career decisions
- · Provide individualized tutorial or remedial instruction to students who require it
- Supervise independent or group projects, field placements, laboratory work or hands-on training
- Supervise teaching assistants
- May provide consultation services to government, business and other organizations

User support technician (2282)

Apr 2017 - Apr 2018

AGENCIA MARITIMA NAVES S.A.S • Barranquilla, Colombia

- Communicate electronically and in person with computer users experiencing difficulties to determine and document problems experienced
- Consult user guides, technical manuals and other documents to research and implement solutions
- Reproduce, diagnose and resolve technical problems encountered by users
- Collect, organize and maintain a problems and solutions log for use by other technical support analysts
- Participate in the redesign of applications and other software
- May supervise other technical support workers in this group.

Analyst, information systems - computer systems

Jan 2014 - Dec 2014

NATIONAL POLICIE CLINIC OF COLOMBIA • Barranquilla, Colombia

My activities to develop within the framework of my functions as an information systems analyst at the National Police Clinic of Colombia in 2014 consisted of:

- Evaluate requirements of the information and communication technology solution according to analysis methodologies and standards.
- Systematize big data according to analytical methods and technological tools.
- · Measure risks according to methodology and business process.
- Test the INFORMATION and communication technology solution according to development tools, procedures and technical parameters.
- Integrate data according to visualization techniques and analysis methodologies.
- Meet customer requirements in accordance with technical procedure and business process regulations.
- Establish requirements of the information and communications technology solution in accordance with standards and technical procedure.

these are some of the functions carried out during my working period with this institution in addition to other activities relevant to technologies such as preventive maintenance, backups, computer networks

Teacher, high school (4031)

Jan 2012 - Apr 2016

ALBERT EINSTEIN SCHOOL COLOMBIA • Barranguilla, Colombia

- Prepare subject material for presentation to students according to an approved curriculum
- Teach students using a systematic plan of lectures, discussions, audio-visual presentations, and laboratory, shop and field studies
- Assign and correct homework
- Prepare, administer and correct tests
- Evaluate progress, determine individual needs of students and discuss results with parents and school officials
- Prepare and implement remedial programs for students requiring extra help
- Participate in staff meetings, educational conferences and teacher training workshops
- May teach and evaluate students through distance or online courses
- May advise students on course selection and on vocational and personal matters
- May supervise student teachers.

EDUCATION

ISO 27001 AUDITOR Jul 2022 - Dec 2022

ACI S.A.U MEMBER OF TUV NORD GROUP • MADRID

- · You must understand the fundamentals and general concepts of information security management.
- You must know the content of the ISO 27001 standard on Information Security Management in
- · You must know what are the components of an ISMS (Information Security Management System).
- You must know how to apply your knowledge about information security audits in any organization to verify compliance with your management system.

SPECIALIST IN DATABASE MANAGEMENT AND SECURITY Mar 2019 - Nov 2019 CENTRO NACIONAL DE APRENDIZAJE SENA • Pereira. Colombia SYSTEMS ENGINEER WITH EMPHASIS ON COMPUTER SECURITY Mar 2017 - Jul 2021 UNIVERSITY FOUNDATION OF THE ANDEAN AREA • Bogota, Colombia INFORMATION SYSTEMS ANALYST Oct 2012 - Oct 2014 CENTRO NACIONAL DE APRENDIZAJE SENA • Barranquilla, Colombia TECHNICAL SPECIALIST IN INFORMATION SYSTEMS Jul 2009 - May 2010 SYSTEMS CENTER INSTITUTE • Barranquilla, Colombia

SKILLS

Thanks to the different trainings received by both the university center from which I am a graduate and the national learning center SENA in Colombia I have been able to develop over the years different skills in digital skills: Creation of digital content for the web with tools such as adobe illustrator. Programming of websites using HTML, CSS, JAVASCRIPT technologies among others, management and management of different databases such as sql server, oracle and

mysql.these are some of the skills in which I have more competences to other than the development in video game in technologies such as Unity 3D, Blender among other computer tools

PROFESSIONAL CREDENTIALS

· Computer engineer

VOLUNTEER WORK

CLASS MONITOR May 2018 - Jul 2019

UNIVERSITY FOUNDATION OF THE ANDEAN AREA • Bogota, Colombia

During the 2018 to 2019 volunteer work was carried out as a class monitor providing students with the possibility of receiving reinforcements from students with the best scores as well as monitoring the learning process to the students who were monitored and report the follow-up to the Office of University Orientation and Permanence of the Foundation Universitary of the area andina in Bogota - Colombia.